Here are a handful of methods that can help you during the understand stage.
在理解阶段 你可以选择很多种辅助方法
I'll give you a quick overview of each of these methods.
我会快速地大概介绍这些方法
The first is 360 degree lightning talks.
首先是 360 度闪电式演讲
As Nadia mentioned, 360 degree lightning talks are incredibly useful.
像 Nadia 提及的 360 度闪电式演讲是非常有用的
The deliverable of the design sprint should meet the business goals,
设计冲刺的产物应符合业务目标
satisfy user needs and be possible with current or emerging technology.
满足用户需求 并且是当前或新兴技术可以达到的
Here are the questions that should be addressed by anyone who
任何演讲人
gives these talks.
应该能解决以下问题
For the business side, that person should be able to address what's
就业务方面 演讲人应该能回答
profitable and sustainable for the business in the long run?
长期来看 业务的利润点与可持续发展性如何？
And what are the current business needs?
当前的业务需求是什么？
Anyone speaking to the user experience should be able to answer,
任何谈论用户体验的人应该能回答
what do people need?
人们需要什么？
And what's delightful or useful to the user?
对用户来说 什么是让人愉悦的或者有用的？
And finally,
最后
someone should be able to speak knowledgeably to technical concerns.
还有人能够在知识的角度上讨论技术问题
What's possible with today's technology?
当前的技术能够达到什么样的程度？
Or what features can be built now or over time?
现在或之后能够完成哪些功能？
Lightning talks are meant to be a quick way to address those major concerns.
闪电式演讲就是要快速地解决这些大问题
Now of any of these activities that you do,
而其他可以选择的活动
you should be sure to do user interviews.
肯定会有用户采访
You want to talk to users at the beginning of the design sprint and
你要在设计冲刺的一开始和最后
at the end of the design sprint, so you can validate your work.
和用户谈话 这样才能确认自己的工作
User interviews allow you to understand the goals and the motivations of users,
通过用户采访 你能理解用户的目标和动机
you might also try exploring some of their emotions and how they feel about
还能了解他们的情绪以及
existing products or about particular features that you want to implement.
他们对现有产品或你想要采用的某种特别功能的感觉
If you have existing designs, you can definitely ask a user about them.
如果手上已经有设计 你可以询问用户对此设计的想法
If not, you could always ask a user about a competitor's design.
如果没有 你可以问用户关于竞争对手的设计的想法
The interview should follow a sort of arc like this.
采访会遵循这个弧线
You want to get to know the interviewee at first,
你需要先了解被采访人
so make them feel comfortable and keep a conversational tone.
让他们觉得舒适 并保持对话的氛围
You also want to be genuinely interested in the person, so
你还需要真正地对这个用户感兴趣
you can ask them starter questions just to build rapport.
这样可以在一开始问一些问题 建立融洽的关系
Then you can plan your questions accordingly, so
然后可以相应地做出问题的计划安排
you can get out their own stories and the general moments in this diagram.
这样可以得到他们自己的背景以及本图中的一些常见时刻
Be sure to thank the user and wrap-up with any followup steps.
记住一定要感谢用户并结尾 进入接下来的步骤
If you don't have any current user research,
如果你没有当前的用户研究
then you should definitely consider going to visit actual users.
你可以考虑访问实际的用户
This would be a field visit.
也就是现场访问
A field visit or
通过现场访问
field study will let you observe how consumers use similar products or
或现场研究 你可以观察消费者如何使用相似产品
you can take note of the context in which users use that product or service.
你还可以记录用户使用产品或服务的背景情况
You can also ask questions about their behaviors, they're likes and
你还可以问他们关于他们的行为的问题 他们喜欢什么
interests and their pain points or problems.
对什么感兴趣 他们的痛点或者问题是什么
You might do usability testing with them, if you have current designs.
如果你当前拥有设计 你可以对他们做可用性测试
Or you might competitor designs, if you don't have current ones.
或者如果你当前还没有设计 你可以使用竞争对手的设计
Or finally, you might gather feedback on early ideas, copy for your webpage or
最后 你可以将对早期创意、网页软文
app and particular features that users may want.
或者用户想要的应用和特定功能的相关反馈集合起来
This would just be concept testing.
这就是概念测试
A stakeholder map is another necessity that can help you think about
另外 利益相关者分析图是帮助你
all the players related to your business or your industry.
考虑与业务或行业相关的所有角色的一种必要方法
For example, the stakeholder map for
比如说 SuperDuper 购物应用的
the SuperDuper shopping app would look like this.
利益相关者分析图是这样的
Notice that this map includes internal stakeholders, such as the user and
请注意 这个图包括内部利益相关者 比如说用户
external stakeholders, like the suppliers and specialists.
以及外部利益相关者 比如供应商和专家
You could imagine building up particular features from recommendations of
你可以根据营养学家或过敏症专科医生的建议
a nutritionist or allergist.
建立特定功能
These specialists might play a role in recommending foods to particular users
这些专家可以根据用户的饮食限制
based on their dietary restrictions, their dietary goals or
饮食目标或烹饪习惯等
their cooking habits.
为特定用户推荐食物
This last activity is another great way to get perspective on the industry.
最后一种活动是获得行业观点的好办法
You can check out competitor's apps or websites to get a sense for
你可以查看竞争对手的应用或网站
what they're doing.
了解他们在做什么
This can help you figure out what's happening in your current space or
这样 你能够明白在你的空间
industry.
或者你的行业正在发生的情况
And you can also analyze, how's your approach different from these others?
你可以分析 你的方法与其他人有什么不同
Is it a subset of features or is it marketing efforts?
是功能的子集或者是营销方面有所不同？
You can also see particular UI elements or design elements and flows,
你还能发现吸引你的用户界面元素或设计元素以及流程
that appeal to you and others that you might want to avoid.
以及其他你想要避免的东西
Whatever methods you choose,
无论你选择哪种方法
you should make sure that you summarize your findings from the activities.
你应该确保你从这些活动中总结了自己的发现
These findings should be on your mind and on the minds of anyone on your team,
这些发现不仅要你自己知道 还需要团队所有人都知道
as you go into the next stage of the design sprint.
这样才能进入设计冲刺的下一个阶段